Guide to the Gianni Emilio Simonetti Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Gianni Emilio Simonetti papers
1960-2017
GEN MSS 1497
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
35.92
(25 boxes)
The Gianni Emilio Simonetti papers, which span from circa 1960 to 2017, contain writings, photographs, posters, and other papers by or relating to Gianni Emilio Simonetti.
Simonetti, Gianni Emilio
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 17 (record albums): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 18 (film): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 19 (born digital): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from L'Arengario Studio Bibliografico on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2017.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Writings, 1960-2017. II. Correspondence, 1965-2017. III. Flyers, Programs, and Documentation From Events and Talks, 1960-2017. IV. Printed Material, 1965-2014. V. Audiovisual Materials, 1965-2016. VI. Electronic Media, 2000-2017.
Gianni Emilio Simonetti
Gianni Emilio Simonetti (1940-) is an Italian multidiscplinary artist, writer, and performer most frequently associated with the Situationist movement and the Fluxus group.
Content Description
The Gianni Emilio Simonetti papers, which span from circa 1960 to 2017, contain writings, photographs, posters, and other papers by or relating to Gianni Emilio Simonetti.
Situationism -- Italy; Situationist literature -- Italy -- 20th Century; Art, Italian; Artists -- Italy -- 20th Century
- Writings, 1960-2017; Series I; 2.17; (2 boxes)
  - Journals and notes, 1970-1979 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes "Parabole Per L'anno 2000", 1980-1992 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 1986-1995 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, circa 1990s (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 1993-2001 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 1996-2005 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 2001-2006 (Box 1)
  - Journals and notes, 2013-2014 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, circa 2007 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, circa 2013 (Box 1)
  - Drafts with corrections and notes with corrections, 1960-2015; 43 folders (Box 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Titles included are Sull'espressionismo in Gernerale, Autonomia E Dipendenza Del Topos Politico, Battery Park, Tesi Sul Fascismo, La Nouvella Cuisine, Quatrtrocento Colpi "Par Rys", Sulla Cultura Della Reazione E La Sua Forma Metapolitica, La Svolta Di Portland, Sulla Glaciazione Teatrale, Pasta Set Multi-Purpose Boiling Unit and Steamer, Madam Bovary O La Forma Del Decoro, Introdusione All'Intelligenza Della Modernita', Il pensiero della pittura pensa la pittura?, Lettera Aperta Ai Veggenti Da Un Non-Vedente, Stato Tecnico E Mondo, Timing, Desabusement Et Matiere De La Critique Dans La Vie Courante, Quaderno Secondo, Bozza Intoduttiva, Thierry Maulnier, Mercadet L'Affarista. Un'Apologia and others.
  - Manuale Di Archeologia Contemporanea, 1962- (Box 2)
  - Cattedra di Food Design, undated (Box 2)
  - GNAM-GNAM, 2009- (Box 2)
  - Labortorio Di Sociologia, 2006-2007 (Box 2)
  - Condimenti - Una Storia Sociale Della Salse, circa 2014-2016 (Box 2)
  - Course materials, "King Kong International", circa 2000-2016 (Box 2)
  - Design degli atti alimentari., 2011-2012 (Box 2)
  - Fluxtales, 2013- (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1965-2017; Series II; 2.58; (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1965-2012 (Box 3)
    Correspondents include Allen de Loach, Edoardo Sanguineti, A. Foner Cohen, Dr. Ricardo Bauer, Allain Arias-Misson, Henry Flint, G. Schneemann, Jeff Berner, Mieko Shiomi, Milan Grygar, Jan van der Mack, Carolee Schneemann, Tim Ulrichs, D. Clive Hardy, The Something Else Press Inc. (Dick Higgins), Andrea Barbate, Luigi Lambertini, Giuseppe Chiari, Maurizio Spatola, John Wilcock, H. Sohm, Urban Gwerder, Frans Denissen, David Briers, Ugo Nespolo, Vittore Querel, Marcel Ianco, Gillian Heiser, Gil Fishman, Bill Balls, John Shuttleworth, Dennis Crompton, Mariarosa Sclauzero, Jack Marchal, Marco Tarchi, Raffaelle Ruffolo, and others.
  - Writings, projects, exhibitions and collaborations with related correspondence, 1967-2006 (Box 3)
    Writings include "APPUNTI PER UN SIRONI AUTRE", "The Tokyo Manifesto of the Spatialism:1968", and others. Correspondents include Maude Nussbaum, Ivo Vroom, Dan Mcleod, Andrea Granchi, Domenico Giuffre, Jeff Keen, Council for Social Development, Veronica Lupton, Kozo Yoshida, Alberto Gini, Riccardo Boglione, C.C. Berg, Riccardo Foglione, Giacomo Mazzone, Paola Bertola, Carl Weissner, David W. Harris, John Esam, E. Battisti, Salvatore Giuliano, Seiichi Niikuni, Angry Arts,
  - Correspondence, 1965-2001 (Box 3)
    Correspondents include Caro Sergio, Ben Vautier, and others.
  - Addressed envelopes, circa 2017 (Box 4)
- Flyers, programs, and documentation from talks and events, 1960-2017; Series III; 15.17; (10 boxes)
  - Ephemera, 1970-1989 (Box 5)
    Flyers, programs and other materials from talks and events attended by Simonetti.
  - Color prints, signed, circa 2007 (Box 5)
  - Porno Grafia and A Dream Hour with Yoko Ono, 1978-; 2013- (Box 5)
  - Clippings and notes, 1977-2017 (Box 5)
  - Fluxus ephemera, 1962-2012 (Box 5)
  - Photographs of Simonetti, 1960-2004 (Box 5)
  - Collage and paintings, 1974-2000 (Box 5)
  - DA AU DELA - "Ready-Game-Bum", 1966-05- (Box 6)
  - DA AU DELA - "Concrete poetry n. 4", 1967- (Box 6)
  - Blank and white hand colored prints, signed, circa 1997-2007 (Box 7)
  - Exhibit print, circa 1997-2007 (Box 7)
  - Paintings, circa 1975 (Box 7)
  - Original and copy of a comic, 1966- (Box 7)
  - Photographs of Simonetti, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-2016 (Box 8)
  - " a pAge from 'Annalyse du Vir.age' ", 1967- (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Vietnam, 1966- (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Remembering the Summer of Love, circa 1967-1971 (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Mostra Di Opera Prima, 1966- (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Poster, The Rock Garden (Pop Music), 1967- (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - The Minimum Definition of Revolutionary Organizations, 1971- (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Centro Arte Viva, 1967- (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Uno, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Du, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Tre, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Quattro, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Cinque, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Otto, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Nova, circa 1966-1967 (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, No Dieci, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, OK Life of USA - Getulio Alviani, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Die Ritulle Kastration - Herman Nitch, 1967- (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Game Around a Revolving Door - Mieko Shiomi, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 1, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 2, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 4, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 5, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 6, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 7, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 8, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 9, 1967- (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Poster, dEDsign 10, circa 1966-1967 (Box 11 (Oversize))
    Poster artwork by Bruno Munari.
  - Poster, Situazione 3, 1967- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Situazione 6, circa 1963-1967 (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Situazione 7, 1967- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Situazione 10, 1967- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, ED912 catalog, 1967- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - "le comite de Action - Treize Questions", 1967-07- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, "...oh Christian Barnard", 1968- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, "Saigonara", 1968- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Club Nuovo Teatro, 1970- (Box 12 (Oversize))
    Poster is in color and signed.
  - Poster, Club Nuovo Teatro, 1970- (Box 12 (Oversize))
    Poster is in black and white.
  - Poster, "RE NUDO", 1970- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, Concert Fluxus, 1969- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, " Inver. No. Vita' ", 1966- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Poster, "...ma l'amor mio non muore", 1971- (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - Paint on canvas, Laboratorio di Arte Terapia, 2008- (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Paint on canvas, Atelier di Arteterapia, 2012- (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Paint on canvas, Atelier di Arteterapia, 2012- (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Paint on canvas, Atelier di Arteterapia, 2013- (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Paint on canvas, Atelier di Arteterapia, 2014- (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Poster, "Gianni Sassi al Lirico - che la festa continui", Circa 1970 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Poster, RE NUDO, circa 1970 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Poster, ROBINUD - anno 1 n.1, circa 1970 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Poster, ROBINUD - anno 1 n.2, circa 1970 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Poster, ROBINUD - anno 1 n.3, circa 1970 (Box 14 (Oversize))
- Printed materials, 1965-2014; Series IV; 4.25; (4 boxes)
  - Gianni-Emilio Simonetti: il corpo il suo d'intorno anche, 1969- (Box 15)
  - La parola mostra il suo corpo: forme della verbovisualità contemporanea, 2008- (Box 15)
  - Apparato Iconografico, circa 2000-2010 (Box 15)
    Printed material is a ring bound catalog.
  - Studio Marconi, 1976-08-14-; 1979-03-22- (Box 15)
  - La Scrittura, 1976- (Box 15)
  - Il La Debole, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Caleidoscopo 8 and 11, 1970-1972; 1972-01- (Box 15)
  - Puzz, number 20, 1975- (Box 15)
  - La Guida Alternativa Alla Cit Ta' Di Milano, 1969- (Box 15)
  - Errata 1 and 2, 1975-03-1976-05 (Box 15)
  - La Fonda 1, 3 and 4, 1974-11-1976-03 (Box 15)
  - Note Critiche Di Agitazione Radicale, 1976- (Box 15)
  - La Critica Ein Anderer Schauplatz, 1974- (Box 15)
  - Zuppa E Pan Bagnato: La Nozione Di Detournement, 1974- (Box 15)
  - Un Poetico Politico, 1979- (Box 15)
  - Musica Laboratatorio 17, 1979- (Box 15)
  - Pallone, 1969- (Box 15)
  - Derive Approdi 17, 1999- (Box 15)
  - In 7, 1972- (Box 15)
  - Sesity, 1968- (Box 15)
  - Da Au Dela, 1965- (Box 15)
  - Fluxfood Concert in Venice, quote tags, 2014-12-04- (Box 15)
  - [Alpha] - beta: laboratorio di critica della cultura visiva, della storia dell'arte, volumes 5-8, 1976- (Box 15)
  - CIA Cook Book, 1972-12- (Box 15)
  - Hyde Park, 1978- (Box 15)
  - L'Esercizio Della Funsione Informativa, 1972- (Box 15)
  - E+O=Ecology, 1970- (Box 15)
  - Le Streghe, circa 1965-1970 (Box 15)
  - Hit, number 2, 1970- (Box 15)
  - Re Nudo 6, 1971- (Box 15)
  - La Gola, 1 and 2, 1982-10-1982-11 (Box 16)
  - L'esoeditoria in italia Le Sperimentazionio - ED912, 2012- (Box 16)
- Audiovisual materials, 1965-2016; Series V; 1.5; (2 boxes)
  - Record albums, 1965-2016
    - Fluxus - Gianni-Emilio Simonetti / Kommissar Hjuler / Magnús Pálsson, 2016-; 1 (Box 17)
    - Finale (1971-1973) - Paolo Castaldi, 1975-; 1 (Box 17)
    - Area II° ‎– Area II°, 1986-; 1 (Box 17)
    - La Caccia (Da Arpocrate Seduto Sul Loto) - Walter Marchetti, 1965-; 1 (Box 17)
    - Cantare La Voce - Demetrio Stratos, 1978- (Box 17)
  - Film, 1971-
    - Teoria Pratica Dell' Architettura, 1971-11-25- (Box 18)
- Electronic media, circa 2000-2017; Series VI; 0.25; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Fluxus Concerts 1 and 2, circa 2000-2017; 2 (Box 19)
  - "MISC" - Gianni-Emilio Simonetti, circa 2000-2017; 1 (Box 19)
  - Visual Music Scores, circa 2000-2017; 1 (Box 19)
  - Drinking a Young Woman in a Dutch Courtyard, 2015-; 1 (Box 19)